chaining multiple prompts together.
You might be wondering, why would you split up a task into multiple prompts when you could
你可能会想，为什么要将任务
分解为多个Prompt，而不是
achieve it with one prompt and chain of thought reasoning like we learned in the previous video?
通过一个Prompt和一系列思维推理来实现呢
？就像我们在上一个视频中学到的那样。
We've already shown that language models are very good at following complex instructions,
我们已经证明，语言模型非
常擅长遵循复杂的指令，
especially the more advanced models like GPT-4.
尤其是像GPT-4这样的更先进的模型。
So let me explain why we would do this with two analogies comparing chain of thought reasoning and chaining multiple prompts.
那么让我用两个类比来解释为什么我们
要比较思维链推理和多个Prompt链。
Using one long, complicated instruction can be like trying to cook a complex meal all
使用一个长而复杂的指令就像
一次性做一桌丰盛的饭菜，
at once where you have to manage multiple ingredients, cooking techniques, and timings simultaneously.
你必须同时使用多种食材、利用高
超的烹饪技巧和掌握好火候。
Chaining prompts, on the other hand, is like cooking the meal in stages where you focus
另一方面，链式Prompt（Chaining prompts）就
像分阶段做一桌饭菜，你可以集中注意力
on one component at a time, ensuring that each part is cooked correctly before moving on to the next.
一次处理一个菜，确保每个菜在
做下一个菜之前都煮好了。
This approach breaks down the complexity of the task, making it easier to manage and reducing the likelihood of errors.
这种方法将任务的复杂性分解，使其
更易于管理，降低出错的可能性。
However, this approach might be unnecessary and overcomplicated for a very simple recipe.
当然，要是做一顿非常简单的饭菜，这
种方法可能是不必要的，过于复杂。
A slightly better analogy for the same thing is the difference between reading spaghetti
对于这件事，对于有些程序经验的
同学来说，一个更好的类比是
code with everything in one long file and a simple modular program.
意大利面条式代码，所有代码都在一个
长文件中，整个程序只有一个模块。
The thing that can make spaghetti code bad and difficult to debug is ambiguity and complex
之所以意大利面条式代码难以阅读并且难
以调试，主要原因是其模糊性和复杂的
dependencies between different parts of the logic.
逻辑部分之间的依赖关系。
The same can be true of a complex single-step task submitted to a language model.
对于提交给语言模型的复杂
单步任务，也是类似的。
Chaining prompts is a powerful strategy when you have a workflow where you can maintain
链式Prompt这种策略很强
大，你设计一个工作流，
the state of the system at any given point and take different actions depending on the current state.
把各种中间状态保存下来，然后根
据当前的状态决定后续操作。
An example of the current state would be after you've classified an incoming customer query,
举一个例子，当客户查询后，你根
据查询的内容对它进行分类，
the state would be the classification, so it's an account question or it's a product question.
那么当前的状态将是分类，从分类结果可以得
知它是一个账户问题或者是一个产品问题。
Each subtask contains only the instructions required for a single state of the task, which
每个子任务很单一，只需要包含执
行子任务所需的指令，这使得
makes the system easier to manage, makes sure the model has all the information it needs
系统更容易管理，确保模型具有
执行任务所需的所有信息
to carry out a task, and reduces the likelihood of errors, as I mentioned.
并减少错误的可能性，正如我前面提到的那样。
This approach can also reduce and lower costs, since longer prompts with more tokens cost
这种方法还可以降低成本，因为Prompt越
长，消耗的Token就越多，成本越高，
Another benefit of this approach is that it is also easier to test which steps might be
这种方法的另一个好处是，它也
更容易测试哪些步骤可能
failing more often, or to have a human in the loop at a specific step.
更容易出错，或者在特定步骤中让人工介入。
So to summarize, because this was a long explanation, instead of describing a whole complex workflow
所以总结一下，因为这是一个很长
的解释，与其在一个Prompt中
in dozens of bullet points or several paragraphs in one prompt, like in the previous video,
用几十个要点或几段文字描述一个复杂的
工作流程，就像在之前的视频中那样，
it might be better to keep track of the state externally and then inject relevant instructions as needed.
不如在外部跟踪状态，然后根
据需要注入相应的指令。
And what makes a problem complex?
那么，是什么使问题变得复杂？
I think in general a problem is complex if there are many different instructions, and
我认为一般来说，如果有很多不同的指令，并且
potentially all of them could apply to any given situation, as these are the cases where
潜在地所有这些指令都可能适用于
任何给定的情况，那么问题就会
it could become hard for the model to reason about what to do.
变得复杂，因为这些情况可能会
让模型难以推理该做什么。
And as you build with and interact with these models more, you'll gain an intuition for
随着您与这些模型的构建和
互动越来越多，您将能
when to use this strategy versus the previous.
更直观的了解，何时使用这种链式Prompt的
策略还是之前一条复杂Prompt的策略。
And one additional benefit that I didn't mention yet, is that it also allows the model to use
还有一点我没提到的额外好处：它还允许
external tools at certain points of the workflow if necessary.
模型在必要时在工作流程的
某些点调用外部工具。
For example, it might decide to look something up in a product catalog, or call an API, or search a knowledge base.
例如，它可以在产品目录中查找某些信
息，或者调用API，或者搜索知识库。
Something that could not be achieved with a single prompt.
这是单个Prompt无法实现的。
So with that, let's dive into an example.
接下来让我们通过一个例子来深入了解。
So we're going to use the same example as in the previous video, where we want to answer
我们将使用与上一个视频相
同的例子，我们想回答
a customer's question about a specific product.
关于特定产品的客户问题。
But this time we'll use more products, and also break the steps down into a number of different prompts.
但这次我们将使用更多的产品，并将
步骤分解为多个不同的Prompt。
So we'll use the same delimiter that we've been using in the previous videos.
我们将使用与之前视频相同的分隔符。
And let's read through our system message.
让我们阅读一下系统消息。
You will be provided with customer service queries.
您将要处理一段客户服务查询。
The customer service query will be delimited with four hashtag characters.
客户服务查询内容会以四个井号字符分隔。
Output a Python list of objects where each object has the following format.
输出一个Python对象列表，其
中每个对象具有以下格式：
Category, which is one of these predefined fields.
类别，这是以下预定义字段之一。
Or products.
或产品。
Where the categories and products must be found in the customer service query.
类别和产品必须在客户服务查询中找到。
If a product is mentioned, it must be associated with the correct category in the allowed products list below.
如果提到了产品，必须将其与下面允
许产品列表中的正确类别关联。
If no products or categories are found, output an empty list.
如果没有找到产品或类别，请输出一个空列表。
And so now we have our allowed list of products.
现在我们有了允许的产品列表。
So we have the categories and then the products within those categories.
所以我们有类别，然后是这些类别中的产品。
So next we have our user message.
接下来我们有用户消息。
And so this message is: "tell me about the smartx pro phone and the fotosnap camera, the dslr one.
所以这个消息是：“告诉我关于smartx
pro手机和fotosnap相机，那个单反的。
Also tell me about your TVs."
还告诉我你们有哪些电视。”
So we're asking about two specific products.
用户询问了两个特定的产品（手机和相机）。
And both of these products are mentioned in the allowed products list.
这两个产品都在允许的产品列表中。
And then we have a television section as well.
然后还有一个电视部分。
Then we format the system message and user message into the messages array.
将系统消息和用户消息格式化为消息数组。
And then we get the completion from the model.
然后我们从模型中得到结果。
And each object has category and products.
每个对象都有类别和产品。
So we have the SmartX Pro phone and the FotoSnap DSLR Camera.
我们有SmartX Pro手机和FotoSnap DSLR相机。
And then in the final object, we actually only have a category because we didn't mention any specific TVs.
在最后一个对象中，我们实际上只有一个类
别，因为我们没有提到任何特定的电视。
And so let's try another example.
那么让我们再试一个例子。
So our second user message is: "my router isn't working."
我们的第二个用户消息是：
“我的路由器不能用。”
And if you notice in the list, we don't actually have any routers.
如果你注意到我们的列表中，
实际上没有任何路由器。
And so as you can see, in this case, the output is an empty list.
如您所见，在这种情况下，输出是一个空列表。
And so now that we have this step to identify the category and products,
现在我们有了这个步骤来识别类别和产品，
if we find any products and categories, we want to load some information about those requested products
如果找到了任何产品和类别，我们希望
将有关这些请求产品的一些信息
and categories into the prompt so that we can better answer the customer question.
和类别，都加入到Prompt中，以便
我们更好地回答客户问题。
And so in our workflow, the state now after this prompt is run is either products have been listed or they haven't been listed.
在我们的工作流程中，现在在这个
Prompt运行之后的状态，要么是列出
了产品，要么是没有列出产品。
And so if I were to actually build this into a system, I might use category names,
如果我要把这个功能真正地构建成一
个系统，我可能会使用类别名称，
maybe something like computers and laptops or something to avoid any weirdness with spaces and special characters.
也许像计算机和笔记本电脑之类的东西，以
避免空格和特殊字符带来的奇怪问题。
But this should work for now.
但现在这应该可以工作。
So now we want to look up some information about the products that the user mentioned.
现在我们想查找一些关于用
户提到的产品的信息。
So about this phone, this camera, and about the TVs in general.
关于这种手机、这种相机和电视机。
And so we need to have some kind of product catalog to look up this information from.
我们需要有个产品目录来查找这些信息。
So as you can see, we have a large number of products available at our store.
如您所见，我们的商店有大量的产品。
And all of these products are fake and were actually generated by GPT-4.
而所有这些产品都是假的，实
际上是由GPT-4生成的。
And so for each product, we have a couple of different fields.
对于每个产品，我们有几个不同的字段，
And so the products is just a dictionary from product name to this object that contains the information about the product.
"products"只是一个从产品名称到
包含产品信息的对象的字典。
Notice that each product has a category.
注意每个产品都有一个类别。
So remember, we want to look up information about the products that the user asks about.
请记住，我们要查找用户询问的产品的信息。
So we need to define some helper functions to allow us to look up product information by product name.
我们需要定义一些辅助函数，以便
根据产品名称查找产品信息。
So let's create a function, get product by name.
让我们创建一个函数，可以
用来根据名称获取产品。
We input the name.
我们输入名称。
And then we're going to return products dictionary, and we're going to get the value for the item with the name as the key.
我们将返回产品字典，我们将从
字典中获取key是name的值。
And then our fallback is just going to be none.
我们的备选方案暂时没有。
And so we also want to define another helper function to get all of the products for a certain category.
我们还想定义另一个辅助函数，
以获取某个类别的所有产品。
For example, when the user is asking about the TVs we have,
例如，当用户向我们询问电视时，
we'd want to load all of the information about all of the different TVs.
我们希望加载所有的不同的电视的所有信息。
So get products by category, input the category name string.
通过输入类别名称来获取类别下的产品。
And to do this, we want to loop through all of the products in the products dictionary,
为此，我们要遍历产品字典中的所有产品，
and check each one to see if the category is equal to the input category.
并检查所有离别和要查询类别相同的产品。
And if so, we want to return that.
如果是这样，我们想要返回这个。
So we'll do this as follows.
我们将按照以下方式进行。
So first, we want to loop through each product, and we have to get the values because we need
首先，我们要遍历每个产品，我们
必须获取值，因为我们需要
to actually access the category, which is in the value.
实际访问值中的类别。
And then we'll return this product if the product category is equal to our input category.
然后，如果产品类别等于我们的输
入类别，我们将返回此产品。
So first, we have a product called the TechPro Ultrabook.
首先，我们有一个名为
TechPro Ultrabook的产品。
So let's get the product information by name.
让我们通过名称获取产品信息。
So here you can see we've just fetched all of the product information.
在这里，您可以看到我们刚
刚获取了所有产品信息。
And let's do an example to get all of the products for a category.
让我们举一个例子，获取一个类别的所有产品。
So let's get all of the products in the computers and laptops category.
那么让我们获取计算机和笔记
本电脑类别中的所有产品。
And just to remember where we are, let's print the user message.
为了记住我们在哪里，让我们打印用户消息。
So the user message was: "Tell me about the SmartX Pro phone and the camera and the TVs."
用户消息是："告诉我关于SmartX
Pro手机、相机和电视的信息。"
And then the initial output from the model from the first step was this.
这就是第一步模型的初始输出。
And so what we also need to do is read this output from the model, which is a string.
还需要做的是阅读模型的这
个输出，它是一个字符串。
We need to pass that into a list so that we can use it as input to the helper functions that we just wrote.
我们需要将其解析成一个列表，以便
输入到刚刚编写的辅助函数中。
So let's write a helper function to do this.
让我们编写一个辅助函数来完成这个任务。
So we're going to use the Python JSON module.
我们将使用Python的JSON模块。
And we're going to write a function called read_string_to_list, a very descriptive title, and input string.
我们将编写一个名为read_string_to_list的
函数，这是函数名很直观，读取字符串到列表。
And so first we'll just check if the input string is none.
首先，我们将检查输入字符串是否为空。
And now we're going to have a try except block to make sure that we catch any errors.
现在我们将加上try except
块来确保捕获任何错误。
And so first we replace any single quotes with double quotes in the input string to
将输入字符串中的任何单引
号替换为双引号，以便
And then we're going to use the JSON loads function to read the input string into the array or the list.
然后使用JSON loads函数将输入
的字符串解析成数组或列表。
And then we're going to return this.
然后将结果返回。
And if there's a decode error, we're going to print the error and then return none.
如果出现解码错误，就打印错误，返回none。
So let's try this with our example.
让我们用之前的例子测试一下。
So we're going to get our category and product list using the read_string_to_list helper function
我们将使用read_string_to_list
辅助函数获取类别和产品列表
And then we're going to print this list.
然后打印解析出来的列表。
So it should look the same.
它应该看起来是一样的。
Let me run this first.
让我先运行这个。
And so as you can see, it's just the same thing except now the type of this variable is actually a list instead of a string.
正如你所看到的，两者的内容是一样的，只是现
在这个变量的类型是列表而不是字符串。
So the whole point of what we're doing is to get the product information into a list
这么做的目的是用一个列
表来保存这些产品信息
that we can add to the next instruction to the model, which is going to be the instruction
接下来将其添加到下一条指令给模型，生成
And so to do this, we need to put the product information into a nice string format that
为了做到这一点，我们需要将
产品信息格式化成字符串，
we can add to the prompt.
然后将其添加到Prompt中。
And so let's also create a helper function to do this.
让我们创建另一个辅助函数来完成这个任务。
So we're going to call it generate_output_string.
我们将它命名为generate_output_string。
And it's going to take in the list of data that we just created.
它将接收我们刚刚生成的数据列表。
So this.
就像这样。
And then I'm going to copy in some code and then we'll walk through what it's doing.
然后我将复制一些代码，然后来讲解它的功能。
So now I'm going to paste in some code and show you an example and then we'll talk about what this function is doing.
现在我将粘贴一些代码，给你们看一个例
子，然后我们将讨论这个函数的作用。
So we're going to get the product information from our first user message.
我们将从第一个用户消息中获取产品信息。
And so we're going to use this helper function generate_output_string on our category and product list,
接下来我们将在类别和产品列表上使用这
个辅助函数generate_output_string，
which if we remember was this.
如果你还记得的话，就是这个。
And so here we have all of the product information for the products that were mentioned in the user message.
在这里，我们有了用户消息中提
到的所有产品的产品信息。
So we have the phone that they mentioned, we have the camera that they mentioned, and
我们有用户提到的手机，有
用户提到的相机，还有
And this is information that will be helpful for the model to be able to answer the user's initial question.
这些信息将有助于模型回答用户的初始问题。
I'll give a brief overview, but you can feel free to pause the video and read it more thoroughly.
我会简要概述一下，但您可以
随时暂停视频并仔细阅读。
So it basically just loops through all of the objects in this list and first checks if there are products.
它基本上只是遍历这个列表中的所
有对象，首先检查是否有产品。
If so, it gets the information for each product and then it checks if there's a category,
如果有，它会获取每个产品的信
息，然后检查是否有类别，
if there weren't any products.
如果没有找到任何产品。
So that would be for this object, for example.
举例来说，这就是类别的对象。
And then it gets all of the product information for the products in that category and it just adds them to this string.
然后它获取该类别中所有产品的产品
信息，并将它们添加到此字符串中。
And then that's what it returns.
然后就是它返回的内容。
So at this point, we've found the relevant product information to answer the user question.
目前为止，我们已经找到了相关的
产品信息来回答用户的问题。
Now it's time for the model to actually answer the question.
现在是时候让模型来正式回复这个问题了。
So let's have our system message.
那么让我们来看看系统消息。
So this is the instruction.
这是指示：
You're a customer service assistant for a large electronics store.
“你是一家大型电子商店的客户服务助手。
Respond in a friendly and helpful tone with, let's say, with very concise answers.
以友好、有帮助的语气回答，我
们可以说，非常简洁的答案。
So we want this to be an interactive experience for the user.
我们希望这对用户来说是一种互动体验。
And so just as a reminder, this was our initial user message.
那么，作为提醒，这是我们最初的用户消息。
I'll just add it again.
我再加一次。
And so now we're going to have our messages array.
现在有了消息数组。
And this is the input to the model.
就是输入到模型的内容。
So let's go through this.
让我们来看看这个。
We have our first message, which is the system message as usual.
第一条消息，像以前一样是系统消息。
We have the user message.
我们有用户消息。
And then we have this additional assistant message.
然后还有这个额外的助手消息。
And this is the message that contains all of the product information that we just looked up.
这里包含了刚刚找到的所有产品信息的消息。
And so we're saying relevant product information, new line, and then this product information that we just found.
这里是相关的产品信息，另起一行，然
后是刚刚找到的这些产品信息。
And so now the model has the relevant context it needs to be able to answer this user's question.
现在模型具有回答用户问
题所需的相关上下文。
So let's get the final response and print it.
那么让我们看看最后返回的结果，并打印出来。
So first it tells the user about the Smart X Pro phone, tells the user about the FotoSnap camera,
首先，它告诉用户关于Smart X Pro手机的信
息，告诉用户关于FotoSnap相机的信息，
and then talks about the different televisions that we have in stock, and then asks the follow-up question.
然后谈论我们现有的不同电
视，最后提出后续问题。
So as you can see, by breaking this up into a series of steps,
如您所见，通过将其分解为一系列步骤，
we were able to load information relevant to the user query
我们能够加载与用户查询相关的信息
to give the model the relevant context it needed to answer the question effectively.
为模型提供回答问题所需的相关上下文。
So you might be wondering, why are we selectively loading product descriptions into the prompt
你可能会想，为什么我们只选择一部分
产品的描述信息加载到Prompt中，
instead of including all of them and letting the model use the information it needs?
而不是包含所有产品的描述信息，让
模型可以从中获取它所需的信息？
And so what I mean by this is, why didn't we just include all of this product information in the prompt,
我的意思是，为什么我们不把所有
产品的信息都包含在Prompt中，
There's a couple of reasons for this.
这其中有几个原因。
Firstly, including all of the product descriptions might make the context more confusing for the model,
首先，包含所有产品描述可能会
使模型的上下文更加混乱，
especially when the context is well-structured like it is in this example,
尤其是当上下文结构良好，
就像这个例子中一样，
and the model is smart enough just to ignore the information that clearly isn't relevant.
而且模型足够智能，可以忽略
那些显然不相关的信息。
The next reasons are more compelling.
接下来的原因更有说服力。
i.e. a fixed number of tokens allowed as input and output.
即允许输入和输出的固定数量的标记。
So if you have a large number of products, imagine you had a huge product catalogue,
如果你有大量的产品，想象一下
你有一个庞大的产品目录，
as you pay per token when using language models.
因为在使用语言模型时，您需
要按消耗的Token付费。
In general, determining when to dynamically load information into the model's context
总的来说，确定何时将信息动
态加载到模型的上下文中
and allowing the model to decide when it needs more information is one of the best ways to augment the capabilities of these models.
并允许模型决定何时需要更多信息，是
增强这些模型能力的最佳方法之一。
And to reiterate, you should think of a language model as a reasoning agent that requires the
再次强调，您应该将语言模型视为一个
necessary context to draw useful conclusions and perform useful tasks.
需要必要的上下文来推理出有用
结论和执行有用任务的代理。
And so in this case, we had to give the model the product information,
所以在这个例子中，我们必
须给模型提供产品信息，
and then it was able to reason about that product information to create a useful answer for the user.
然后它能够根据该产品信息进行
推理，为用户创建有用的答案。
And in this example, we only added a call to a specific function or functions to get the product description by product name,
在这个例子中，我们只添加了一个调用特定功
能或功能的方法，根据产品名称获取产品描述，
or to get the category products by category name.
或者根据类别名称获取类别产品。
But the models are actually good at deciding when to use a variety of different tools,
但是，这些模型实际上擅长决定
何时使用各种不同的工具，
And this is the idea behind chatGPT plugins.
这就是ChatGPT插件背后的原理。
We tell the model what tools it has access to and what they do,
我们告诉模型它可以使用哪些
工具以及每个工具的功能，
and it chooses to use them when it needs information from a specific source or wants to take some other appropriate action.
当它需要从特定来源获取信息或采取其他
适当行动时，它会选择使用这些工具。
In our example, we can only look up information by exact product and category name match,
在我们的例子中，我们只能通过精确
的产品和类别名称来查找信息，
but there are also more advanced techniques for information retrieval.
但还有更先进的信息检索技术。
Embeddings can be used to implement efficient knowledge retrieval over a large corpus to find information related to a given query.
嵌入（Embedding）可以用于在大型
语料库上实现高效的知识检索，以
找到与给定查询相关的信息。
One of the key advantages of using text embeddings is that they enable fuzzy or semantic search,
使用文本嵌入的一个优势是
它支持模糊或语义搜索，
which allows you to find relevant information without using the exact keywords.
这样你可以使用自然语言而不
是关键词找到相关信息。
So in our example, we wouldn't necessarily need the exact name of the product,
所以在我们的例子中，不一
定需要产品的确切名称，
but we could do a more a search with a more general query like a mobile phone.
但我们可以使用更通用的查
询进行搜索，例如“手机”。
We're planning to create a comprehensive course on how to use embeddings for various applications soon, so stay tuned.
我们计划不久后开一个关于如何将嵌入
（Embeddings）应用于各种应用的全面课程，敬
请期待！
And with that, let's move on to the next video where we're going to talk about:
好了，让我们继续观看下一个
视频，接下来我们将讨论：
how to evaluate the outputs from the language model.
“如何评估语言模型的输出结果。”